A Guide to the Martha Baird Rockefeller papers FA467
Rockefeller Archive Center
Martha Baird Rockefeller papers
1886-1971 Bulk, 1951-1971
1951-1971
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller, Martha Baird (1895-1971)
FA467
26.68 Cubic Feet 25 letter document boxes, 3 legal document boxes and 12 record storage boxes
Housing -- Boxes 1-28 - document boxes. Boxes 29-30 - oversized flat boxes. All other boxes are record cartons.
Biographical/Historical note
Martha Baird Rockefeller (March 15, 1895 - January 24, 1971), the second wife and widow of John D. Rockefeller, Jr., was a world-class classical pianist in the 1920s, giving concerts across the U.S. and throughout Europe.
Martha Baird was born in Madera, California, the second child of William F. Baird (1861-1916), a coal operator and merchant, and the former Mina A. Smith (1862-1903), a musician. Martha's first public performance was in June 1903, when, at the age of 8, she played "In the Gypsies' Camp" on piano in a concert at the University of Southern California's College of Music, where her mother taught piano and organ. Martha studied with Morton F. Mason, a composer and organist in southern California. She graduated from the Blairsville (Pennsylvania) School for Girls and attended Occidental College in Los Angeles. In 1915 she entered the New England Conservatory of Music. In May 1917 she won the school's annual piano competition, which earned her a $1,200 grand piano as the grand prize. That spring she graduated with highest honors from the school's soloist course.
On November 14, 1917, Martha Baird gave her first public recital at Boston's Jordan Hall. Her performance was well received by the Boston Globe but Philip Hall of the Boston Herald thought that she had "not yet learned to think musically at all times for herself." On March 22, 1920, Martha Baird made her New York debut at the Princess Theater at 104 West 39th Street. On August 4, 1920, she married Adrian van Laar, an importer; they divorced in Paris in 1925. During her marriage, Martha Baird continued to perform under her own name, and on October 5, 1923, "the famous American pianist" made her debut in London at Wigmore Hall.
On May 20, 1930, in the study of Dr. Harry Emerson Fosdick, Martha Baird was married to Arthur M. Allen, a lawyer, of Providence, Rhode Island. Some discussions of her career indicate that she retired from performing after her marriage to Allen, but she did not stop entirely. By the mid-1930s her appearances were concentrated around Boston and Providence, and she devoted more time to the Providence Symphony Orchestra, especially its concerts for young people. In May 1937 she was elected president of the Providence Community Concert Association, serving in that capacity until 1950. In 1940 she wrote the music to accompany Helen Church's lyrics for the Republican party campaign anthem, "We Want Willkie."
Arthur Allen died on May 6, 1950. On August 15, 1951, Martha Baird Allen married John D. Rockefeller, Jr., whose wife Abby had died in 1948. Arthur Allen had been a Brown University classmate and a friend of John D. Rockefeller, Jr., so that Martha Baird had known JDR Jr. for some time. As a wedding present, JDR Jr. gave his bride a trust fund so that she could experience the joy of giving that he had known.
Martha Baird Rockefeller used her new wealth, and the $48 million she inherited upon her husband's death in 1960, to support her chosen field of music as well as causes identified with the Rockefeller family. In 1957, she established the Martha Baird Rockefeller Fund for Music, a private philanthropy that responded to various needs she saw in the field of music. Incorporated in 1962, the Fund's interest centered on young solo artists, who received support directly through individual grants or indirectly through contributions to performance organizations that offered advanced training and employment in important capacities. Until Mrs. Rockefeller's death in 1971, the Fund was supported by her contributions of $600,000 annually. Her will provided for an unrestricted bequest to the fund of $5,000,000, and the trustees elected to continue the program at the same level until funds were exhausted. The Fund was dissolved in 1982.
Conditions Governing Access note
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Material in the Rockefeller family collections that provides the names, correspondence, or activities of living members of the Rockefeller family, and/or documents the net wealth of any Rockefeller family members, is restricted. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Rockefeller Brothers Fund, Inc. donated the Martha Baird Rockefeller papers to the Rockefeller Archive Center in January 1982. The papers were initially transferred to the Rockefeller Family Archives (Rockefeller Family & Associates) in April 1971 and June 1972 at which time a preliminary appraisal was conducted and the material was accessioned. The Martha Baird Rockefeller papers were then physically transferred to the Rockefeller Archive Center on January 14, 1982.
Scope and Contents note
The Martha Baird Rockefeller papers consist of correspondence, scrapbooks, photo albums, personal memoranda books, house books, and sheet music. The majority of these papers were maintained at her home by Martha Rockefeller or her personal staff and were never part of files maintained at the Rockefeller Family Office in Room 5600 of Rockefeller Center (except Series 4).
The Martha Baird Rockefeller papers also contain financial and estate records, plus office files created and maintained by Mary Packard. Series 4 consists of Martha Baird Rockefeller's files maintained at Room 5600.
Arrangement note
Series 1: Correspondence. Subseries 1: Individuals. Subseries 2: Organizations. Subseries 3: Baird family. Subseries 4: Martha Baird Rockefeller personal. Subseries 5: Possessions. Subseries 6: Osteopathy. Subseries 7: Medicine. Subseries 8: Giving Program. Subseries 9: Homes. Subseries 10: Martha Baird Rockefeller Fund for Music. Subseries 11: Rockefeller family philanthropy. Subseries 12: Rockefeller family correspondence. Subseries 13: Political.
Series 2: Scrapbooks and Photo Albums. Series 3: Personal Memoranda Books and House Books. Series 4: Room 5600 (Rockefeller family office) File. Series 5: Office Files (Mary Packard files)
Series 6: Private, Financial, and Estate Inventories, Appraisals & Distributions. Subseries 1: Medicine. Subseries 2: Trusts. Subseries 3: MBR Will. Subseries 4: Accounts. Subseries 5: 740 Park Avenue. Subseries 6: Political. Subseries 7: JDR Jr. Estate. Subseries 8: MBR Estate. Subseries 9: Card Catalouges.
Series 7: Clippings and Annual Reports. Series 8: Piano Music.
The files contained in Series 1-3 were placed in their present file arrangement by Martha Baird Rockefeller.
- Correspondence, 1; 8.36 Cubic Feet 22 letter document boxes
  - Individuals, 1.1
    - A Miscellaneous (Box 1)
      Scope and Contents note
      Invitations; appeals.
    - Albright, Horace M., 1961; 1964-1965 (Box 1)
      California trip; tributes to JDR, Jr.
    - Anderson, M. Roy., 1961; 1967 (Box 1)
      Crank; objected to MBR aid to MAR.
    - B Miscellaneous (Box 1)
      MBR'personal gifts to friends; invitations declined; old friends.
    - Barbour, Lyell, 1929; 1951-1952; 1954; 1956; 1954-1965. (Box 1)
      Pianist, MBR personal interest; gifts; his concerts.
    - Belmont, Mrs. August, 1953-1954; 1956-1957 (Box 1)
      Invitations; opera.
    - Bird, Mr. and Mrs. Remsen, 1955; 1957-1967 (Box 1)
      Personal friends; personal news; his activities in retirement; rift; loss of MBR friendship.
    - Branch; Hope, 1956-1968 (Box 1)
      Personal friend; personal news, MBR gift.
    - Burton, Margaret E., 1961-1968 (Box 1)
      MBR gifts to her.
    - C Miscellaneous. (Box 1)
      Crank letters; appeals; small personal gifts; invitations.
    - Campbell, Percival, 1955; 1967 (Box 1)
      Sends JDR, Jr. a silk handkerchief.
    - Chase, Mary Ellen, 1952; 1954-1956 (Box 1)
      Personal friendship; visits.
    - Choi, Rosa, 1953-1954 (Box 1)
      Aid to student at Manhatten School.
    - Chorley, Kenneth, Mr. and Mrs., 1951-1953; 1955-1956; 1958; 1960-1968 (Box 1)
      Personal friendly letters; gift of clothes; news of Williamsburg; JY Ranch.
    - Columbo, Irma, 1964; 1967-1970 (Box 1)
      MBR aid to niece of hairdresser; gift to Irma.
    - Coolidge, Arlan R, 1951; 1954; 1962-1967; 1970 (Box 2)
      Brown professor; personal friend; gifts; music in Providence.
    - Craddock, Mrs. K. Vera, 1952; 1954-1955; 1957-1960; 1962-1970 (Box 2)
      Conditions Governing Access
      Restricted from access - Personnel.
    - Crowley, Marjorie, 1966-1967 (Box 2)
      Appeal for aid declined.
    - D Miscellaneous (Box 2)
      Friends; cranks; small gifts; invitations.
    - Dendramis, Mary, 1954-1958; 1961-1963; 1966. (Box 2)
      MBR gifts to widow of Greek ambassador; personal friend.
    - F Miscellaneous (Box 2)
      Invitations; small personal gifts.
    - Form Letter Responses (Box 2)
      Forms for letters declining contributions or appointments.
    - Fosdick;, Henry E. and Raymond B., 1955-1956; 1961-1962; 1965-1966 (Box 2)
      RBF on JDR, Jr. biography and Karsh photograph; HEF on Christmas flowers.
    - Fox, Virgil, 1952-1956; 1960-1961 (Box 2)
      Organist at Riverside Church; MBR not satisfied with music in church, too loud.
    - Fraser, Grace, 1951; 1965-1966 (Box 2)
      Providence friend; personal gifts.
    - Fulton, Betty, 1966-1968 (Box 2)
      "Aunt Martha"; news of her family.
    - G Miscellaneous (Box 2)
      Invitations; deaths; appeals.
    - Gifts Received, 1956-1957 (Box 2)
    - Glauser, Gertrude, 1954-1955; 1957-1959 (Box 2)
      Conditions Governing Access note
    - Goldthorpe, John, 1960; 1963-1965; 1969. (Box 2)
    - Graf, Dr. Herbert, 1962 (Box 2)
      Wrote book, "Producing Opera for America."
    - Greece, King and Queen of, 1953-1958; 1960; 1962-1966 (Box 2)
      Meeting; Christmas greetings; photographs.
    - H Miscellaneous (Box 2)
    - Harmon, Frances S., 1957; 1961-1963; 1965-1966. (Box 2)
      MBR gifts to active volunteer in Inter-Church Center work, WRVR.
    - Hayes, Roland, 1955; 1958; 1960-1970 (Box 3)
      His career; MBR annual and special gifts.
    - Hess, Dame Myra, 1933; 1962; 1965. (Box 3)
      MBR gift to her; birthday tribute.
    - Holtman, Jan, 1953-1954; 1963. (Box 3)
      MBR gift to aid Polish pianist.
    - Hutt, Mary K, 1956-1959; 1961-1968; 1970-1971. (Box 3)
      MBR gifts and annuity; work in Africa; commitment continues; personal news.
    - I L Miscellaneous (Box 3)
      Comment on MBR playing Chopin; gift of tickets to students at International House; crank letters; flowers on death of friends; invitations declined; friends.
    - Lang, Paul Henry, 1962 (Box 3)
      Music critic comments on new opera productions.
    - Larsen, Charlotte, 1960-1963 (Box 3)
      MBR gifts; she died in 1963.
    - Lasker, Mary (Mrs Albert), 1956-1962 (Box 3)
      Plans for beautifying Park Avenue.
    - Lawson, E. Gertrude, 1958; 1960; 1962-1966 (Box 3)
      MBR gifts to Providence musician.
    - Lawson, James R. (Box 3)
      Riverside Church carillonneur; tribute to JDR, Jr.; difficulties.
    - Leader, Lewis, 1962 (Box 3)
      Porcelains for sale.
    - Lefevre, Kamiel, 1960 (Box 3)
      Retires as carillonneur of Riverside Church.
    - Letters - Old, Personal - Miscellaneous (Box 3)
      From Lyell Barbour, Mrs. John Gardner, Mrs. Eleanor Coats, Ila W. Curtain, Sam Dushkin, Rose K. Furd
    - M Miscellaneous (Box 3)
      Small gifts to former employees; appeals declined.
    - Mayer, Sir Robert, 1957; 1960 (Box 3)
      Regarding Arthur Schnabel and his music.
    - McCracken, Robert J., 1960-1962 (Box 3)
      MBR aid to him during illness of his wife.
    - McKenzie, A. J., 1965 (Box 3)
      Appeal for funds declined.
    - McManus, George S., 1957; 1959; 1965-1968 (Box 3)
      Met MBR in Berlin in 1922; studied with Schnabel.
    - Miner, George, 1962; 1964-1966 (Box 3)
      JDR, Jr. classmate; friendship; visits.
    - Monath, Hortense, 1953; 1955-1956 (Box 3)
      MBR aid for pianist.
    - Moran, Delia, 1951; 1954; 1956-1958; 1963-1964; 1967 (Box 3)
    - Moran, Kathleen, 1966 (Box 3)
    - N Miscellaneous (Box 3)
    - Nesmith, Edith, 1968 (Box 3)
    - Norris, Ruth, 1956; 1958-1961; 1963-1965; 1969 (Box 3)
    - Oldham, Harold, 1962-1965 (Box 4)
      MBR gift.
    - P Miscellaneous (Box 4)
      Appeals; Nathan Pusey on JDR, Jr.
    - Petremont, Charles, 1957-1958; 1960-1961. (Box 4)
      MBR gift to violinist.
    - Putnam, Palmer C., 1961-1964; 1966-1967 (Box 4)
      Owed JDR, Jr. money; MBR purchased debt from his estate, forgave debt.
    - R Miscellaneous (Box 4)
      Appeals declined; wedding congradulations.
    - Reid, Josephine, 1965 (Box 4)
      Claimed to have known MBR, wanted to arrange meeting, not answered.
    - Relatives, Pseudo, 1955; 1960; 1961; 1965; 1968 (Box 4)
      Claims of relationship which did not exist.
    - S Miscellaneous (Box 4)
      Appeals; contribution to SHARE.
    - Sanger, Margaret, 1954; 1958; 1960; 1966 (Box 4)
      Friendship; Mrs. Sanger's plans; her death.
    - Schnabel, Arthur, 1925-1927; 1929-1930; 1933; 1941 (Box 4)
      Friendly letters from German pianist.
    - Schnabel Memorial Committee, 1951-1953; 1956; 1959; 1961; 1965 (Box 4)
      MBR comments on association with Schnabel; teaching techniques; friendship with widow and son.
    - Sharpe, Mrs. Henry D. (Mary Elizabeth), 1951; 1953-1954; 1961-1965; 1967; 1969-1970 (Box 4)
      Providence friends; friendship; appeals for special projects defined.
    - Shumway, Agnes, 1960-1961; 1964-1970 (Box 4)
      Memories of California; best wishes.
    - Sittig, Margaret, 1954-1955; 1960-1971 (Box 4)
      MBR gifts to violinist and her father who played at Bar Harbor.
    - Stokowski Recording Proposal, 1963 (Box 4)
      MBR declines to make contribution to project.
    - Suchanek, Molly, 1966 (Box 4)
      MBR gift to former employee.
    - Sundermeyer, Mrs. Wilhelm (Babs), 1954-1955; 1957-1970 (Box 4)
      Sister of Mary Hutt; MBR gift to her and her son.
    - Tash, Mrs Agnes, 1958-1960 (Box 4)
      MBR sent CARE packages to her in Yugoslavia.
    - Towne, Charles W., 1964 (Box 4)
      JDR, Jr. and AMA classmate at Brown, Tucson resident.
    - Trouve, John, 1958-1962; 1964-1970 (Box 4)
      Thanks for gifts.
    - U - V Miscellaneous (Box 4)
      Contributions to UCPH; UN Hospitality Fund; United Fund of Rhode Island; Anne Vanderbilt and Mrs Everett Colby, personal friends; appeals declined.
    - Vetrano, Anthony, 1961 (Box 4)
    - Voorhies, Earl, 1959; 1961; 1964-1965 (Box 4)
      Pianist; appeals for aid declined; was childhood neighbor; remembers "Miss Beard" concert pianist.
    - W Miscellaneous (Box 4)
      Appeals; small gifts; invitations.
    - Willis, Helen, 1961-1963; 1965; 1967-1968 (Box 4)
      Personal friend; personal news.
    - Winston, Edith Tuck, 1955-1956; 1959-1969 (Box 5)
      Personal friend; personal news and activities.
    - X - Z Miscellaneous (Box 5)
      Shnabel's niece writes about recordings; photographs of Yosemite.
  - Organizations, 1.2
    - Miscellaneous Declinations, 1952-1959; 1962-1971 (Box 5)
      Appeals declined; general information; taxes on gifts.
    - Miscellaneous Donations, 1954-1955; 1958; 1960; 1969-1970 (Box 5)
      New gift tax and fund raising laws, 1954; MBR gifts and contributions to: Isidor Philipp Fund; Teton National Park Headquarters recreation hall; Tucson Symphony Orchestra; player piano to Wiltwyck School for Boys; Santa Fe Oprera; National Council on Crime and Delinquency; Third Street Music School Settlement.
    - Academy of Political Science, 1970 (Box 5)
      MBR financing of study of NAR state papers.
    - American Hymnal, 1954-1960; 1968-1970. (Box 5)
      Title for collection of hymns; pledge; contributions.
    - American Opera Society, 1971 (Box 5)
      Approval for aid; no action taken.
    - American Red Cross, 1951; 1953; 1955; 1962-1963; 1966; 1968; 1970 (Box 5)
      Resignation after marriage; contributions through United Fund; personal friendships; data on Red Cross and MBR service; DSC memos advising gifts; MBR gifts.
    - Beneficent Church, Providence, RI, 1954; 1956-1957; 1959; 1961. (Box 5)
      Contributions; death of Elmer Westcott and Howard Allen.
    - Bennington College, 1954; 1956-1959; 1961; 1963-1964 (Box 5)
      Contributions.
    - Blood Center, NY, 1963-1965; 1968 (Box 6)
      MBR contribution to Blood Center.
    - Boston Symphony Orchestra, 1943; 1948-1949; 1963; 1966-1971 (Box 6)
      1949 Tribute to Serge Koussevitzky on his retirement; MBR contributions.
    - Brown University, 1937; 1947; 1951-1952; 1955-1957; 1959; 1961-1971 (Box 6)
      MBR gifts; invitations; endowment for books; piano; aid to students; JDR, Jr. Library Dedication; Class of 1897 alumni photographs including JDR, Jr. and AMA; Judge F. B. Perkins comments on MBR gifts; Brown University Alumni Monthly.
    - California, 1959; 1961; 1966-1968; 1970 (Box 6)
      Los Angeles Music Center; Palomar; miscellaneous.
    - City Temple, London, 1954-1955; 1961 (Box 6)
      MBR contributions.
    - Cleveland Museum of Art, 1958; 1960-1961 (Box 6)
      Bequest of Lawrence portrait of Lady Dysart by JDR, Jr.
    - Committees, 1966 (Box 6)
      MBR declines service.
    - Concert Artists Guild, 1964 (Box 6)
      Award to JDR 3rd at dinner.
    - Cooper Union, 1956; 1958 (Box 6)
      MBR gifts of artifacts.
    - Councils of Churches, National and World, 1963-1969 (Box 6)
      Report of JDR, Jr.'s 1958 gift.
    - Council on Foreign Relations, 1965; 1967-1968 (Box 6)
      MBR gift of $300,000; MBR votes.
    - Egypt, Abu Simbel, 1962; 1965; 1967-1968 (Box 7)
      MBR contribution.
    - French Causes, 1960 (Box 7)
      Contribution.
    - Friedberg Music Foundation, 1956 (Box 7)
      MBR gift to purchase music library for Columbia University.
    - Frick Collection, 1962; 1966-1967. (Box 7)
      Clippings.
    - Great Smokies Trip, 1954 (Box 7)
      Diary and maps.
    - Greece, 1961-1964; 1966 (Box 7)
      JDR, Jr. memorial tablet in the Agora, Athens.
    - Harvard University, 1957; 1967-1969 (Box 7)
      Clippings, Divinity School contribution; correspondence; MBR declines service on committee to visit music department.
    - Harvard University. (Box 7)
    - Harvard University: Frank L. Hinckley Fund, 1959 (Box 7)
      MBR gift to Law School in honor of Frank L. Hinkley.
    - Hong Kong Christian Center, 1963 (Box 7)
      MBR gift through National Council of Churches.
    - Inter-Church Center, 1954-1955; 1957-1958; 1960; 1962-1964; 1968; 1970 (Box 7)
      Clippings; plaque to JDR, Jr.; MBR gift toward purchase of organ.
    - International Piano Library, 1969 (Box 7)
    - Invitations, 1961-1962; 1964 (Box 7)
      Declined
    - Lincoln Center, 1961; 1963-1964; 1966; 1968; 1970 (Box 7)
      Contributions; clippings on art; passes and I. D. cards.
    - Lincoln Center: Beaumont Theater, 1967 (Box 7)
      Anonymous MBR contribution.
    - Los Angeles Music Center, 1962; 1964 (Box 7)
      Appeals declined.
    - Edward McDowell Association, 1952-1954 (Box 7)
    - Manhattan School of Music, 1952-1953; 1962-1963; 1965; 1969 (Box 7)
      Contributions; problems at school.
    - Mannes College of Music, 1963-1964 (Box 7)
    - G. C. Marshall Research Foundation, 1961; 1964; 1966. (Box 7)
    - Memberships (Box 7)
      List of memberships on boards.
    - Memorial Center for Cancer and Allied Diseases, 1954-1955; 1964 (Box 7)
    - Metropolitain Museum of Art, 1952; 1955-1958; 1960-1971 (Box 7)
      Clippings; invitations to activities; Having request for loan of Duccio refused by MBR; gift of Angelica Kauffman doors and French tapestry chairs - MBR held life interest; gift of lace; MBR fellow in perpetuity; thanks for Rockefeller gifts; Temple of Dendur interest, verbal pledge; membership card, 1970.
    - Metropolitan Opera: General, 1951-1953; 1958-1959; 1962-1963 (Box 7)
      MBR contributions to Lincoln Center; artists; program Opera Guild; programs; clippings; MBR gifts for new productions, incidentals; relations between MBR Fund and Metropolitan; Metropolitan Opera Association, MBR as member, 1962, Board of Directors, 1963; minutes of Metropolitan Opera board of directors, MBR service on committees; pledges for new productions.
    - Metropolitan Opera: General, 1964-1970 (Box 8)
    - Metropolitan Opera: MBR Sponsored Productions, 1954-1961; 1964 (Box 8)
      $700,000 for Faust, Andrea Chenier, Magic Flute, Eugene Onegin, Fidelio, A Masked Ball, Die Meistersinger, Falstaff, plans for Othello in 1972, DSC comments.
    - Metropolitan Opera: MBR Sponsored Productions, Fan Mail, 1954-1970 (Box 8)
      Public gratitude for new productions, includes comments on City Center productions; Kirsten Flagstad Memorial Fund.
    - Metropolitan Opera: Scrapbook, 1953-1968 (Box 8)
    - Mount Desert Island Hospital, 1960 (Box 8)
      Contribution
    - Multiple Sclerosis Society, 1959-1960 (Box 8)
    - Music Clubs, 1952-1953; 1961 (Box 8)
      MBR contribution to Rhode Island Federation of Music Clubs.
    - Musicians Benevolent Fund, 1960-1962 (Box 8)
      MBR contribution in tribute to Miss Gertrude Norman.
    - Musicians Club of America, 1964 (Box 8)
      Contribution; correspondence with Ada H. Miller.
    - Netop Restorations, Inc., 1963 (Box 8)
      MBR contribution to Rhode Island restoration (house in Providence).
    - New England Conservatory. (Box 9)
    - New England Conservatory: General, 1941; 1949-1950; 1952; 1954-1956; 1958; 1961; 1964-1968; 1970 (Box 9)
      MBR contributions; invitations; citation; problems of conservatory; accounts of her career printed in 1970 pamphlet; concert handbills.
    - New England Conservatory: Minutes of Trustee Meetings, 1956-1957; 1961-1962; 1965-1970 (Box 9)
      MBR member of board of trustees; minutes of meetings, (MBR did not attend).
    - New England Conservatory: Mason & Hamlin Award, 1966-1970 (Box 9)
      MBR won this piano competition in 1917; asked to write remebrances of the competition and her career for the NEC alimni newsletter.
    - New England Conservatory: Dana S. Creel, 1964-1970 (Box 9)
      MBR correspondence with DSC on the needs and activities of NEC.
    - New England Conservatory: Class of 1917 50th Reunion, 1967-1968 (Box 9)
      MBR did not attend, contribution for class gift to NEC.
    - New York City Cancer Committee, 1953-1955 (Box 9)
    - New York City Center (and Opera): Miscellaneous, 1966-1969 (Box 9)
      Clippings and some correspondence regarding productions and performers.
    - New York City Opera: Dana S. Creel, 1970-1971 (Box 9)
      Correspondence between MBR, DSC and Julius Rudel, director of NYCO regarding needs and activities of NYCO; MBR pledges.
    - New York City Opera: MBR Miscellaneous, 1962-1966; 1970 (Box 9)
      Clippings, program schedules, some correspondence.
    - New York City Opera: 1964/65, 1965/66 Seasons, 1963-1965 (Box 9)
      Plans for productions; MBR pledges.
    - New York City Opera: 1969/70 Season (Box 9)
    - New York City Opera: MBR Sponsered Productions: "Don Rodrigo", 1966 (Box 9)
      Clippings and correspondence.
    - New York City Opera: MBR Sponsered Productions: "Julius Caesar", 1966 (Box 9)